Reclaiming the Right to Rock: Black Experiences in Rock Music Collection, 2008-2010
Indiana University Digital Library Program
- 1. Conference Sessions, 2009 November 13 and 14, All HD QuickTime files have the following derivative copies: Online streaming access is available for some items with IU log in credentials. Researchers in need of streaming access can contact the AAAMC to request an IU guest account. Links to streaming content, when available, are included in each item's description below. Medium resolution QuickTime files (video: 960 x 540, deinterlaced, 29.97 fps, codec h.264; audio: linear PCM, stereo, 16-bit/48 kHz) Low resolution QuickTime files w/embedded timecode windows (video: 480 x 270, deinterlaced, 29.97 fps, codec h.264; audio: linear PCM, stereo, 16-bit/48 kHz) Video discs (DVD) Copies of the digital image files are available on DVDR 15 and include deaccessioned items (e.g., photos that were blurry, underexposed, redundant, etc.
  - Session 1. "What Is Rock? Definition and Roots," 2009 November 13, DVF 1039--DVF 1041; DIF 2133--DIF 2171; MDV 16--MDV 17; 3 video files (HD QuickTime) (3 hours, 54 minutes): sound, color; 60.75 GB + 1 transcript (24 pages), 39 digital photographs (color), 2 videocassettes (HD miniDV, 107 minutes: sound, color); Hollinden, Andy; Crazy Horse, Kandia; Stew; Willis, Ike; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services; McAlpin, Michael; Batcheller, Anna
    Description
    This panel examines the following broad areas: (1) the ways in which African American rock musicians conceive of and define rock as a musical genre; (2) how rock is situated within the broader spectrums of African American music and American popular music; (3) the social and political context for the emergence of this music; and (4) the role of rock in African American community life. Video files consist of 14 sec. calibration pattern and 117 minutes of footage from main camera and 117 minutes of simultaneously recorded footage from side camera.
    Online Streaming in Media Collections Online
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/6537034f9s
    Technical Note
    File DVF 1039 contains a test pattern/calibration screen for the panel. One file each created by main and side cameras.
  - Session 2. "The Politics of Rock: Race, Class, Gender, Generation," 2009 November 14, DVF 1049--DVF 1052; DIF 2048--DIF 2085; 4 video files (HD QuickTime) (3 hours, 51 minutes): sound, color; 63.06 GB + 1 transcript (33 pages), 38 digital photographs (color); Garofalo, Reebee; Mitchell, Moe; Tamar-kali; Tate, Greg; Tillery, Linda; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services; Sewald, Ronda L.
    This panel explores the role of race, class, gender, and generation in shaping the multiple identities of participants in rock, as well as the ways that African American rock musicians have negotiated these identities within the context of the music industry, mainstream society, and African American communities. Video files consist of 29 sec. calibration pattern and 115 minutes of footage from main camera and two files totaling 115 minutes of simultaneously recorded footage from side camera.
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/6537034g2w
    File DVF 1049 contains a test pattern/calibration screen for the panel and DVF 1051 contains no useable content. One file each created by main and side cameras.
  - Session 3. "Face of Rock in the 21st Century," 2009 November 14, DVF 1053--DVF 1055; DIF 2086--DIF 2132; 3 video files (HD QuickTime) (4 hours, 27 minutes): sound, color; 70.94 GB + 47 image files (jpeg: color); Mahon, Maureen; Fields, Rob; Netic; Thomas, Kamara; Thomas, Suzanne; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services; Batcheller, Anna; Sewald, Ronda L.
    This panel explores the status of rock in the 21st century—how rock is conceptualized/defined and how has it been transformed and reinterpreted; the role of African American musicians in this process; current trends in rock; the use of technology for creative, marketing and distribution approaches; the reception of Black rockers by the music industry, mainstream, underground, and international audiences; and African American communities, etc. Video files consist of 34 sec. calibration pattern and 134 minutes of footage from main camera and 133 minutes of simultaneously recorded footage from side camera.
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/6537034g5t
    File DVF 1053 contains a test pattern/calibration screen for the panel. One file each created by main and side cameras.
  - Man on the Street Interviews, 2009 November 14, DVF 1042--DVF 1048; 7 video files (HD QuickTime) (14 minutes); Allbrittin, Deanna; Berry, William; Brown, Clayton; Ford, Starla; Rizzi, Jessica; Rowley, Ariel; Williams, Lorrin[?]; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services
    Brief interviews with audience members attending Saturday conference sessions. Due to technical problems, an additional interview with an unidentified informant was not recorded and a second interview with another unidentified informant was recorded without audio.
    File DVF 1042 contains no useable content.
- 2. One-on-One Interviews, 2009 November 12-14, All HD QuickTime files have the following derivative copies: Online streaming access is available for some items with IU log in credentials. Researchers in need of streaming access can contact the AAAMC to request an IU guest account. Links to streaming content, when available, are included in each item's description below. Medium resolution QuickTime files (video: 960 x 540, deinterlaced, 29.97 fps, codec h.264; audio: linear PCM, stereo, 16-bit/48 kHz) Low resolution QuickTime files w/embedded timecode windows (video: 480 x 270, deinterlaced, 29.97 fps, codec h.264; audio: linear PCM, stereo, 16-bit/48 kHz) Video discs (DVD) File DVF 1019 contains a test pattern/calibration screen for the panel.
  - Crazy Horse, Kandia, 2009 November 13, DVF 1027; MDV 13; 1 video file (HD QuickTime) (34 minutes): sound, color; 8.88 GB + 1 transcript (8 pages), 1 videocassette (HD miniDV: sound, color); Garofalo, Reebee; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services; McAlpin, Michael
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/653703487s
  - Douglas, Jr., Earl, 2009 November 13, DVF 1025--DVF 1026; MDV 13; 2 video files (HD QuickTime) (38 minutes): sound, color; 9.97 GB + 1 transcript (8 pages), 1 videocassette (HD miniDV) (sound, color); Garofalo, Reebee; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services; McAlpin, Michael
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/653703484v
  - Fields, Rob, 2009 November 13, DVF 1035--DVF 1037; 3 video files (HD QuickTime) (36 minutes): sound, color; 9.30 GB + 1 transcript (8 pages); Orjuela, Fernando[?]; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/6537034c3c
  - Mitchell, Moe, 2009 November 13, DVF 1029--DVF 1031; MDV 13; 3 video files (HD QuickTime) (39 minutes): sound, color; 10.33 GB + 1 transcript (9 pages), 1 videocassette (HD miniDV: sound, color); Garofalo, Reebee; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services; McAlpin, Michael
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/653703489d
  - Netic, 2009 November 13, DVF 1033--DVF 1034; MDV 14; 2 video files (HD QuickTime) (24 minutes): sound, color; 5.30 GB + 1 transcript (5 pages), 1 videocassette (HD miniDV: sound, color); Mahon, Maureen; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services; McAlpin, Michael
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/6537034972
  - Spooner, James, 2009 November 13, DVF 1032; MDV 13; 1 video file (HD QuickTime) (27 minutes): sound, color; 7.00 GB + 1 transcript (5 pages), 1 videocassette (HD miniDV: sound, color); Mahon, Maureen; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services; McAlpin, Michael
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/653703493t
  - Stew, 2009 November 12, DVF 1023--DVF 1024; MDV 1; 2 video files (HD QuickTime) (53 minutes): sound, color; 13.99 GB + 1 transcript (15 pages), 1 videocassette (HD miniDV: sound, color); Hollinden, Andy; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services; McAlpin, Michael
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/6537034630
  - Tamar-kali, 2009 November 14, DVF 1038; 1 video file (HD QuickTime) (29 minutes): sound, color; 7.74 GB + 1 transcript (9 pages); Garofalo, Reebee; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/6537034c1r
  - Thomas, Kamara, 2009 November 13, DVF 1028; MDV 13; 1 video file (HD QuickTime) (36 minutes): sound, color; 9.44 GB + 1 transcript (6 pages), 1 videocassette (HD miniDV: sound, color); Mahon, Maureen; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services; McAlpin, Michael
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/653703495f
  - Thomas, Suzanne, 2009 November 12, DVF 1020; 1 video file (HD QuickTime) (25 minutes): sound, color; 6.50 GB + 1 transcript (7 pages); Burnim, Mellonee; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/653703440h
  - Tillery, Linda, 2009 November 12, DVF 1021; 1 video file (HD QuickTime) (36 minutes): sound, color; 9.46 GB + 1 transcript (9 pages); Hollinden, Andy; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/653703426t
  - Willis, Ike, 2009 November 12, DVF 1022; MDV 1; 1 video file (HD QuickTime) (36 minutes): sound, color; 9.63 GB + 1 transcript (9 pages), 1 videocassette (HD miniDV: (sound, color); Hollinden, Andy; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services; McAlpin, Michael
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/653703422k
- 3. Conference-Related Events, 2009 October 19-November 20
  All HD QuickTime files have the following derivative copies:
  Online streaming access is available for some items with IU log in credentials. Researchers in need of streaming access can contact the AAAMC to request an IU guest account. Links to streaming content, when available, are included in each item's description below.
  Medium resolution QuickTime files (video: 960 x 540, deinterlaced, 29.97 fps, codec h.264; audio: linear PCM, stereo, 16-bit/48 kHz)
  Low resolution QuickTime files w/embedded timecode windows (video: 480 x 270, deinterlaced, 29.97 fps, codec h.264; audio: linear PCM, stereo, 16-bit/48 kHz)
  Video discs (DVD)
  Copies of the digital image files are available on DVDR 15 and include deaccessioned items (e.g., photos that were blurry, underexposed, redundant, etc.
  - Reclaiming the Right to Rock: Black Experiences in Rock Music Exhibit, 2009 October 19-November 20, DIF 1984--DIF 2001; CDR 24--CDR 25; 18 image files (jpeg): color + 2 audio discs (CD); Wilkins, Langston; Nelson-Strauss, Brenda; Batcheller, Anna
  - Film Screening of Passing Strange followed by Q&A Session with Stew, 2009 November 11, DAF 289; DIF 2172--DIF 2212; 1 audio file (33 minutes): stereo; 24-bit/44.1 kHz, 501.11 MB + 41 image files (jpeg: color); Stew; Estrada, Zilia C.
    Audio recording is of Q&A session only.
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/6537034f00
  - Ike Willis Classroom Lecture to Andy Hollinden's Frank Zappa Class, 2009 November 12, MDV 2--MDV3; DAF 286--DAF 287; DIF 1519--DIF 1654; 2 videocassettes (HD miniDV) (65 minutes): sound, color + 1 audio file (101 minutes: mono; 24-bit/48 kHz, 1.62 GB), 1 audio file (104 minutes: stereo; 24-bit/44.1 kHz, 967 MB), 136 image files (jpeg: color); Willis, Ike; Estrada, Zilia C.; Estrada, Zilia C.; Walter, Rich
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/6537034f6v
  - Suzanne Thomas Workshop/Rehearsal with the IU Soul Revue, 2009 November 12, MDV 7--MDV 11; 5 videocassettes (HD miniDV) (197 minutes): sound, color; Thomas, Suzanne; IU Soul Revue; Kreiger, Meryl; McAlpin, Michael
    In addition to workshop/rehearsal, the videocassettes contain footage of three brief man on the street interviews with IU Soul Revue members recorded by Michael McAlpin.
  - Kandia Crazy Horse and Kamara Thomas Dinner/Discussion at Hutton Honors College, 2009 November 12, DIF 1839--DIF 1870; 32 image files (jpeg): color; Crazy Horse, Kandia; Thomas, Kamara; Estrada, Zilia C.
  - Linda Tillery Workshop/Demonstration on Negro Spirituals at Collins Living-Learning Center, 2009 November 12, DIF 2002--DIF 2047; 46 image files (jpeg): color + 6 audio files (wav, 18 minutes: mono; 16-bit/44.1 kHz); Tillery, Linda; Unidentified student from Paul Mahern's "Audio production" course; Estrada, Zilia C.
  - Ike Willis Lecture/Workshop at Foster International Living-Learning Center, 2009 November 12, MDV 4--MDV 6; DAF 288; DIF 1655--DIF 1838; 3 videocassettes (HD miniDV) (127 minutes): sound, color + 1 audio file (wav, 96 minutes: stereo; 24-bit/48 kHz), 184 image files (jpeg: color); Willis, Ike; Wallner, Jessie; McAlpin, Michael; Walter, Rich; Ozdegirmenci, Izlem
    Includes two brief man on the street interviews with audience members in addition to lecture/workshop footage.
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/6537034f47
  - Suzanne Thomas Lecture to Professor Mellonee Burnim's Class "From Juke Joint to Choir Loft," 2009 November 13, MDV 12; DIF 2340--DIF 2402; 1 videocassette (miniDV) (50 minutes): sound, color + 63 image files (jpeg: color); Thomas, Suzanne; Cooper, Kailee; Ozdegirmenci, Izlem
  - "Who Are Asian Pacific Americans?" Luncheon Talk Series at Asian Culture Center, Featuring Suzanne Thomas, 2009 November 13, MDV 15; DAF 290 (copy on CDR 84); DIF 2277--DIF 2307 (copies on CDR 83); 1 videocassette (HD miniDV) (45 minutes): sound, color + 1 audio file (wav, 55 minutes: stereo; 16-bit/44.1 kHz), 31 image files (jpeg: color); Thomas, Suzanne; Fales, Cornelia; Lee, Mike
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/6537034f2m
  - Afro-punk Film Screening Followed by Question and Answer Session with Director and Co-Producer James Spooner, 2009 November 13, DIF 2308--DIF 2323 (copies on CDR 83); 6 audio files (wav) (approximately 24 minutes)on DVDR 9: mono; 16-bit/44.1 kHz) + 16 digital photographs (color); Spooner, James; Unidentified student from Paul Mahern's "Audio Production" course; Lee, Mike
  - Union Board Concert Featuring the IU Soul Revue, Suzanne & The Blues Church, and Tamar-kali, 2009 November 14, DVF 1056--DVF 1064; DVDR 10--DVDR 14; DIF 1456--DIF 1518; DIF 2213--DIF 2276; MDV 18--MDV 25; 9 video files (HD QuickTime) (2 hours, 51 minutes): sound, color; 44.6 GB + 1 videodisc (DVD: sound, color), 4 videodiscs (DVD with AVCHD files: sound, color), 8 videocassettes (HD miniDV, 448 minutes: sound, color), 240 image files (jpeg: color); IU Soul Revue; Thomas, Suzanne; Blues Church (Musical group); Tamar-kali; Indiana University, Radio and Television Services; Monroe County Public Library, Community Access Television Services; Guest-Scott, Anthony; Wallner, Jessie; Hatlen, Merrill; Hsu, Hsin-Wen; Batcheller, Anna; Lee, Mike
    Techincal Note
    File DVF 1056 contains a test pattern/calibration screen for the concert.
    http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/6537034g8r
- 4. Miscellaneous Audiovisual Materials, 2009 November-December
  - Appreciation Banquet Photographs, 2009 November 14, DIF 2324--DIF 2339 (copies on CDR 83); 16 image files (jpeg): color; Lee, Mike
  - Suzanne Thomas Luncheon and Union Board Concert Volunteer Footage, 2009 November 13-14, MDV 26--MDV 27; 2 videocassettes (HD miniDV) (122 minutes): sound, color; Thomas, Suzanne; Teo, Bertrand
    Additional footage recorded by journalism student for use in a classroom podcast project.
  - Portia Maultsby Interview; Suzanne Thomas Interview, approximately 2009 November 13, MDV 28; 1 videocassette (HD miniDV) (52 minutes): sound, color; Teo, Bertrand
    Footage recorded by journalism student for use in classroom podcast project; also includes three "man on the street" interviews with conference attendees.
  - Podcast Project Files for Paul Mahern's "Audio Production" Class, 2009 November 11-14, DVDR 9; 35 audio files (wav) (approximately 29 minutes): mono; 16-bit/44.1 kHz on DVD-R.; Students enrolled in Telecommunications T-353
    Brief, edited audio clips recorded by volunteer journalism student for use in final classroom podcast project for Paul Mahern's "Audio production" course. Consist primarily of man on the street interviews recorded with audience members attending the film screening of Passing Strange, the Union Board concert, as well as clips from a one-on-one interview with AAAMC director Portia K. Maultsby and Afro-punk director and co-producer James Spooner. Original audio recordings no longer exists.
  - Final Podcast Projects from Paul Mahern's "Audio Production" Class, circa 2009 December, CDR 20--CDR 23; 4 audio files (wav) (approximately 19 minutes) on 4 data CDs: mono; 16-bit/44.1 kHz; Kilpin, Jordan; Powell, Gary; Lamping, Nicholas; Davis, Gareth
    Four of the final classroom podcast projects created for Paul Mahern's "Audio Production" course created from interviews and audio from various panels and related events recorded by Mahern's T-353 students throughout the course of the conference.
- 5. AAAMC Production Materials, 2009 March-2010 January
  - Event and Volunteer Schedules
    - Summary of Conference Week Events
    - RTVS Filming Schedule
    - Volunteer and Staff Schedules/Itineraries
  - Panelist/Moderator Itineraries
    - The Blues Church
    - Crazy Horse, Kandia
    - Fields, Rob
    - Garofalo, Reebee
    - Hollinden, Andy
    - Mahon, Maureen
    - Mitchell, Moe
    - Netic
    - Spooner, James
    - Stew
    - Tamar-kali
    - Tate, Greg
    - Thomas, Kamara
    - Thomas, Suzanne
    - Tillery, Linda
    - Willis, Ike
  - Publicity Materials
    - Information for Event Calendar Postings, 2009 September 28
    - Conference Website, 2009 October, http://www.indiana.edu/~aaamc/br/brconf_2009.html
    - Conference Website (pdf version), 2009 October
    - AAAMC Black Rock Discography/Filmography, 2009 October
    - Liner Notes (no. 13), 2008-2009, http://www.indiana.edu/~aaamc/PDFs/linernotes13.pdf
      Contains edited version of pre-conference interview with Linda Tillery and a description of the upcoming conference.
    - Liner Notes (no. 14), 2009-2010, http://www.indiana.edu/~aaamc/PDFs/linernotes14.pdf
      Contains extensive conference coverage and edited interviews with Stew, Ike Willis, Earl Douglas, and Tamar-kali.
  - Administrative documents
    - Linda Tillery Pre-Conference Interview, 2008 September 8, 1 audio disc (CD): stereo; 4 3/4 in. + 1 transcript (15 pages); Cooper, Tyron; Tillery, Linda
    - Maureen Mahon Pre-Conference Interview, 2009 September 8, 1 audio disc (CD): stereo; 4 3/4 in. + 1 transcript (12 pages); Cooper, Tyron; Mahon, Maureen
    - New Frontiers Grant Proposal, 2009 January 19
    - Panelist Invitation Letters, 2009 March 27
    - Purchasing Contract Template for Panelists'/Moderators' Services, 2009 May 12
    - Themester Funding Proposal, 2009 May 24
    - Participants' Acceptance of Conference Invitation Confirmation Letter, 2009 June 12
    - Travel Information Form, 2009 July 21
    - Panel Descriptions and Proposed Interview/Panel Questions, 2009 July
    - Information Request for IU-AAAMC Purchasing Contract, 2009 July 22
    - Material Donation Request Letter and Response Form, 2009 July 22
    - Revised Purchasing Contract Templates, 2009 August 7
    - Conference Registration Form, 2009 September 22
    - Travel and Hotel Summaries for Conference Participants, 2009 September-November
    - Documenter and Audience Member Release Form Templates, 2009 November
    - Conference Program, 2009 November
    - CD of Introductory Music for Conference Sessions, 2009 November
    - New Frontiers Final Grant Report, 2010 January 27